(Massachusetts, USA)
美国 马萨诸赛州
Boy wonder Hiroki Sawada, at a tender age of 10,
天才少年泽田弘树年仅10岁
is a graduate student at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology.
就已经是麻省理工学院的研究生了
His development of the method of tracking a person's ancestors
他通过皮肤和血液资料追溯人类祖先
using skin and blood data,
而开发出让人大为震惊的 "DNA探查程序" 想必大家仍然记忆犹新
And Hiroki is now developing a mechanical brain,
目前弘树正在着手开发一种 生长一年等于人类五年的自我成长人工智能
This is been fully supported by the top of the IT industry,
全力支持此项目的 则是IT界巨头辛多拉公司的汤玛斯辛多拉社长
Hiroki's parents divorced two years ago.
弘树的双亲于两年前离婚
Hiroki parted with his father
他离开了父亲
and moved to America with his education-minded mother.
跟着热心教育的母亲移民到美国
With his mother died of an illness, and Hiroki was left all by himself,
辛多拉社长收养了 后来因母亲病逝而孤单一人的弘树
It is said that the mechanical brain Noah's Ark will be
人工智能"诺亚方舟" 号称是人类史上最伟大的发明
And Hiroki is placed in tight security.
弘树受到了严密的保护
He's not allowed to play in the park like a normal child.
他无法像普通小孩一样在公园玩耍
Noah's Ark is a reference to Noah's ark in the Old Testament.
诺亚方舟是出自于旧约圣经中的故事
God created a big flood to purge corruption from the world,
上帝为了一扫地上的罪恶而掀起了一场大洪水
and only Noah, who had followed God's way,
上帝只允许符合他心中理想的诺亚打造一艘方舟
that his family and a variety of animals could ride.
让其家人和各种动物上船
So that they could escape the big flood.
因此他们逃过了这场洪水的浩劫
(Noah's Ark)
（诺亚方舟）
Boss, there's something strange.
老板 情况有点奇怪
The phone line. It looks like the program data...
程序数据好像通过一般的电话线路……
Hiroki, what are you doing?
弘树 你在做什么
Noah's Ark sailed out.
诺亚方舟 出航
Goodbye, my friend.
再见了 我的朋友
Open up, Hiroki!
快开门 弘树
What are you doing?
你在做什么
Hiroki!
弘树
Will I be able to fly like Noah's Ark?
我是否能跟诺亚方舟一样飞起来呢
Hiroki, where are you?
弘树 你在哪里
Hiroki!
弘树
Boss!
老板
Look at that!
你看这个
(Noah's Ark Sailed Out)
（诺亚方舟 已出航）
(Good-bye HIROKI) (Noah's Ark Sailed Out)
（再见了 弘树）
(Detective Conan The Phantom of Baker Street)
名侦探柯南 贝克街的亡灵
I am a high school detective, Shinichi Kudo.
我是高中生侦探工藤新一
When I went to the amusement park
当我跟青梅竹马的同学毛利兰
with my childhood friend, Ran Mouri,
一起到游乐园玩时
I witnessed a suspicious transaction made by a man in black.
却目击了黑衣人进行可疑交易的现场
I was too preoccupied with watching at that time,
当时我只顾着偷看
and didn't notice another accomplice approaching from behind.
却忽略了从背后靠近的另一个同伙
He made me take the poison by force.
我被那个人强行灌下了毒药
When I woke up,
等我醒来时
my body became smaller.
我的身体已经缩小了
If those guys knew that Shinichi Kudo was still alive,
要是让那些家伙知道工藤新一还活着
not only would my life be in danger,
不但我的性命难保
but I would also endanger my families and friends around me.
还会危及到我身边的亲人
At the suggestion of Professor Agasa,
在阿笠博士的建议下我隐瞒了身份
When Ran asked for my name,
当小兰问及我的名字时
without time to think it over, I took the name of Conan Edogawa.
情急之下我化名为江户川柯南
In order to collect information about those guys,
为了收集那些家伙的情报
I moved in with Ran whose father is a detective.
就住进了父亲是侦探的小兰家中
Are you ready?
大家准备好了吗
Among them, the only one who knows my real identity,
在他们之中知道我真正身份的
except the Professor,
除了博士之外
is Ai Haibara.
就只有灰原哀一个人了
She used to work with those men in black,
她本来跟黑衣人是一伙的
but when she escaped from the organization,
但是从组织中逃出来时
she took the same drug as me,
因为吃了跟我一样的药物
so her body has also become smaller.
身体也变小了
And these are my parents who, no matter how old they are,
还有不管年纪多大总是喜欢恶作剧的
always like playing pranks and always act like little children.
活像小孩子的我的父母
My father is a world-renowned mystery novelist.
我父亲是世界知名的推理小说家
Speaking of the "Dark Baron" series by Yusaku Kudo,
提到工藤优作的"暗夜男爵"系列
it's universally known to all the reasoning enthusiasts.
推理爱好者可谓无人不知
My mother, Yukiko Kudo, was a legendary idol actress
母亲工藤有希子是个20岁就隐退结婚的
who retired and got married at the age of 20.
传说中的偶像女星
But now she's just a nagging granny.
但现在只是个啰嗦的阿婆而已
For now, I am ostensibly the child of their distant relatives.
我表面上暂时被当作他们俩人远房亲戚的孩子
I haven't seen them lately.
最近一直都没见到他们
I don't know how my parents are doing.
爸爸和妈妈不知过得如何
I'm doing well.
我过得很好哦
Although my body is smaller, my mind is still flexible.
身体虽然变小 但头脑依旧灵活
I am the famous omniscient detective.
无所不知的名侦探
Only one truth will prevail!
真相永远只有一个
(Two Years Later)
（两年后）
(Beika City, Tokyo) (Beika City Hall)
（东京都 米花市） （米花市政大厅）
Right here, at the Beika City Hall,
这里 在米花市政大厅
Japanese game makers and Schindler Company
日本的游戏厂商与辛多拉公司共同开发的
will soon hold the grand first presentation
体验虚拟游戏
of their co-developed virtual experience game.
即将举行盛大的首次发布会
President Schindler of Schindler Company has arrived at the site.
现在辛多拉公司的辛多拉社长抵达了现场
According to the information sent to us,
根据发给我们媒体的资料
this game, also nicknamed "Cocoons",
这个被昵称为"茧"的游戏
allows players to enter the cocoon-like capsules
让玩家进入蚕茧般的胶囊中
and play in the virtual world
在催眠的状态下
under hypnosis while conversing with the game
与具备语音识别系统的游戏 一边对话
that has a voice recognition system.
一边在虚拟世界中游玩
We can say that this game is a collection of
可以说是一个集合了最新科技精华的游戏
The game provides five scenarios for players to enjoy.
这个游戏提供了5种供玩家们自由游玩的场景
What exactly is this virtual world really like?
究竟是个怎样的虚拟世界
The children will find out the answer after today's experience.
等孩子们今天体验过后便会知晓
The presentation will not be open to the public.
完全是一个不对外公开的发布会
50 children from junior high and elementary schools
获选参加的50名初中及小学的孩子们
will be the first to experience "Cocoons" in Japan.
将成为日本最初的"茧"体验者
I can't understand!
真是的
It's just a presentation on an ordinary video game.
不就是场电视游戏的发布会而已
Why are they making such a big deal about it?
干嘛搞得这么夸张
I heard that even before this presentation,
听说在举行这场发布会之前
there are already many commercial spies working on it.
就已有商业间谍在暗地里展开各种活动了
It's said that the emergence of "Cocoons"
据说因为"茧"的出现
will change the whole video game world in one fell swoop.
将一举改变整个电玩界的版图
What's that thing?
那是什么东西啊
Could it be that...
难道这
those are "Cocoons"?
那就是"茧"啊
I want to play "Cocoons" too!
我也好想玩"茧"啊
That's impossible.
那是不可能的
Although we were invited to this party,
我们虽然被邀请参加晚会
we weren't chosen to experience "Cocoons".
但并没有被选上成为"茧"的体验者
But, actually, to experience historical events in the game
但是能在游戏中体验历史事件
is quite interesting to me.
我倒是有点兴趣
Yeah!
是啊
It feels like we travel back in time, right?
感觉就像是在参加真正的时光旅行
It's just a game, that's all.
只不过是个游戏而已吧
Conan-kun, you're not good at video games, right?
柯南不擅长电子游戏的 对吧
You haven't even finished the "Space Dragon" yet.
到现在连"太空恶龙"都还没有打通关呢
I guess your fingers are not very nimble.
手指头好像不怎么灵活啊
Stop nagging.
啰嗦
(At the party venue)
社交宴会会场
So many people! And so much wine!
人好多 酒也好多
Dad!
爸爸
The top brass in the police department seems to be here too.
警局的高层好像也来了
Don't drink too much.
不要喝得太多啦
I know.
知道啦
I won't get drunk on the finest wines.
喝高级酒是不会醉的
That's not what she meant.
不是这个意思啦
This is an all-you-can-eat buffet, isn't it?
这里应该是随便吃的吧
I guess so.
大概是吧
Lucky me! Lucky me!
运气好 运气好
The lucky ones should be those kids.
运气好的应该是那些孩子啦
Look, they're getting their badges for the game.
看他们正在领参加游戏的胸章
I guess they are the kids
想必他们就是传说中被选上参加游戏的孩子们吧
Grandson of the deputy director of
警视厅副总监的孙子
Grandson of a capitalist in the financial world.
金融界资本家的孙子
Son of a ruling party politician.
执政党政治家的儿子
The second and third generations responsible for Japan's future
肩负着日本未来的第二三代全都到齐了
I can feel people jealously staring at us.
可以感受到他人嫉妒的眼神吧
This is the epitome of the ugly hereditary rule in Japan.
简直就是日本丑恶世袭制的缩影
Along with this hereditary rule,
伴随着这种世袭制
the history of human evil will be repeated again and again.
人类的错误历史也将不断的重演
I don't know what any of those words mean, Haibara-san.
灰原 你在说什么我听不懂啊
Haibara.
你啊
Didn't I tell you to speak like a child?
不是告诉过你要用小孩子的口气说话吗
The son of a politician will become a politician.
政治家的儿子将成为政治家
And the son of a banker will become a banker.
银行家的儿子也会成为银行家
At this rate, no matter how long it takes,
这样下去 无论过多久
Japan will not change.
日本还是不会改变
Blah, blah, blah...
等等 等等
There were a lot of things like that in yesterday's news.
昨天的电视新闻里说了好多哦
How's that? Happy now?
怎样 这样可以吧
So scary.
好可怕
Ran!
兰
Sonoko.
园子
Hi, boys and girls.
嗨 男孩女孩们
Sonoko-san, is that badge...
园子姐姐 那个胸章不会是……
You mean this one?
这个吗
Did you get chosen too?
难道园子也被选上了吗
Because our Suzuki Group also financed their game development.
因为铃木财团也出资赞助了游戏开发
That's so nice.
真好啊
I want it too!
我也好想要啊
Give up!
死心吧
We are not in the same position.
立场不一样啦
Come to think of it, were you really invited?
再说 你们真的有被邀请吗
How can you be that rude?
太失礼了吧
I personally invited these kids, okay?
这些孩子可是我邀请的客人
Isn't this the young lady from the Suzuki Group?
这位不是铃木财团的千金吗
You know what,
你们知道吗
a person's life has been determined since birth.
人在出生的时候就已经决定他的一生了
Yeah, that's right.
是啊是啊
Even beautiful clothes choose their owners.
漂亮的衣服也会挑选穿它的主人的
Those who are not chosen can only stand around,
没有被选上的人在一旁含着手指看着就行了
These guys are really annoying.
这帮家伙真让人不爽
Dad, you should come teach them a lesson!
爸爸 你也说说他们呀
Listen up, youngsters.
听好了 少年们
Don't be this naive about life.
不可以把人生看得太天真
Even in a seemingly smooth life, there can be pitfalls.
看似顺利的人生也会有陷阱
You will see what I am saying when you grow up.
等你们长大之后就会明白
Like your wife would run away or something?
像老婆跑掉之类吗
I know things about you.
我知道的哦 大叔的事情
Sleeping Kogoro.
沉睡的小五郎
It's because your wife run away while you were asleep
是睡着时让老婆逃掉了才会有这个绰号的吧
You brats...
这些小鬼
It's not while sleeping!
才不是在睡觉的时候呢
Mom left while Dad was in the bathroom.
妈妈是在爸爸上厕所的时候离开家的
Am I right?
对吧
You are not making this better.
真是越帮越忙
Come on, let's play a mini soccer game.
来 我们踢场迷你球赛吧
Thinking of these kids inheriting their fathers' businesses
一想到这帮孩子将会继承父辈的事业
and being Japan's future leaders,
成为日本将来的领导人
the future seems really hopeless.
未来可真是令人绝望啊
I feel the same way.
我有同感
What are you doing?
你干什么
Give it back to me.
还给我
You're disturbing other guests.
这会打扰其他的客人
If you want to play, go outside.
想玩的话到外面去
Who are you, old man?
你是谁啊 大叔
I'm the development director of "Cocoons", Kashimura.
我是"茧"的研发负责人 坚村
It's because my grandfather's sponsorship
是因为我爷爷的银行提供资助
that you're able to complete this game, isn't it?
你们才能够完成游戏的 对吧
Didn't your parents ever teach you about public morality
你们的父母没有教你们什么叫作公共道德吗
and how to talk to seniors?
还有对长辈的说话方式
Look how cocky you are!
了不起死了
We don't lend you any more money!
不借你钱了
Old man, I guess you don't know us, do you?
大叔 你是不是不认识我们
If you dare to mess with us,
如果和我们作对
you'll lose your job tomorrow!
明天就要被炒鱿鱼了哦
Well, then before that,
那么 在这之前
I'll get you out of here first.
让我先把你们从这里赶出去吧
Go.
走吧
Wow, what a handsome man!
哇 好帅的大叔啊
Not like someone else.
跟某人可完全不一样
Shinichi should be here too.
新一应该也来了
You haven't seen each other in so long,
你们好久没见了 应该想来个单独的父子团聚吧
Professor, please keep our relationship under wraps.
博士 关于我跟他的关系要这个哦
I know it.
我知道了啦
Ladies and gentlemen, please take note of the stage.
各位来宾 请注意一下舞台
Now, Mr. Yusaku Kudo, who helped design the scenes for "Cocoons",
现在 为"茧"的场景设计提供创意的
has already arrived from the United States.
工藤优作先生已经从美国赶来了
Oh boy, he's finally back!
哎呀 终于回来啦
I just wondered where you'd been this month.
我想你这个月去哪儿了呢
So you went to help with my father's work.
原来是帮爸爸做事去了
I went to help him finish the final stage of the project.
我去帮他完成程序的最后阶段
Where's my mom?
妈妈呢
She said she hadn't been back to Japan for too long.
她说好久没回日本了
So she went to a classmates' party.
所以去参加同窗聚会了
Here, your gift.
来 这是给你的礼物
The badge for the game?
参加游戏的胸章
I'm happy, though,
虽然很高兴
I can't go playing this game alone.
但我不能一个人跑去玩啊
I was just thinking you'd love it.
我想你应该会迷上它吧
Although it's still not public yet,
虽然这还是秘密
this game is set in London a hundred years ago,
不过游戏是以一百年前的
that is to say, in the late 19th century.
19世纪末的伦敦为舞台的
London a hundred years ago?
一百年前的伦敦
Dad hasn't changed at all. He still loves that world that much.
老爸一点没变 还是这么喜欢那个世界
You are just the same as your father.
你们父子俩都一样
So dark.
真黑啊
I can't see anything.
什么都看不见了
I'm sorry.
不好意思
Annoying.
真是的
Don't run around in the dark, okay?
不要在漆黑一团的时候到处乱晃
Next,
接下来
please enjoy this next-generation game machine, "Cocoon".
就请诸位欣赏这台次世代游戏机"茧"
This capsule is equipped with five kinds of human senses.
这个舱体掌握着人类的5种感觉
Whether sense of touch, sense of pain, or sense of smell,
无论是触觉 痛觉 还是嗅觉
all the senses will expose players to a world
所有的感觉 都会将玩家置身于跟现实一样的世界中
It stimulates the central nervous system through electricity,
它是通过电力来刺激中枢神经系统
which is completely harmless to the human body.
对身体完全无害
It's so boring to stand by and watch.
只是看而已 好无聊啊
Only by participating in can the game be fun.
游戏还是亲自玩才有趣
Oh, you're all here.
哦 大家都在啊
So, just to kill time, let's guess a riddle.
那么为了打发时间 就来猜个谜语吧
Here he goes again.
又要开始了
The Professor's classic boring riddle that makes people cold.
博士的冷谜语
Run away?
溜吧
He must have worked hard to come up with it.
一定是他很努力想出来的
Let's just let him speak it out.
就让他说说看吧
Mr. A of this game company
这家游戏公司的A先生
couldn't help but get totally hooked on
在工作时禁不住迷上了玩"茧"
After seeing that scene, what would his boss do with Mr. A?
看到这个情况的老板 怎样处理A先生呢
First, commended him for winning the game.
一 因为到最后打通游戏 表彰了他
Second, fired him for playing the game at work.
二 因为在上班时玩游戏 开除了他
Third, let him keep sleeping in "Cocoon"
三 因为在茧中睡得很熟 就让他继续这样睡下去
Third, let him keep sleeping.
三 让他继续这样睡下去
Why?
为什么啊
Because "Cocoon" looks like a cradle.
因为"茧"的样子很像摇篮
That's not true.
不对
I choose the first, commend him.
我觉得是一 表彰
That's not true either.
那个也不对
So the answer is the second, but why?
那么答案是二咯 为什么啊
Ai-kun, you should know the reason, right?
小哀你应该知道为什么吧
Can you explain it for me?
能帮忙说明一下吗
I'm not wearing much today.
我今天穿得很少
So please ask Edogawa-san for help.
所以还是拜托江户川吧
Hey, she named you.
喂 被点名了哦
"Cocoon" is referring to the silkworm cocoon.
"茧"就是指蚕茧
And the one who spits out the silk to make the cocoon
而吐丝结茧的就是蚕（kaiko）
In other words,
换句话说
Kaiko has another meaning in Japanese, that is, dismissal.
解雇（kaiko）就是开除的意思
So cold.
好冷
I'll go get a hot drink.
我去拿热饮过来
I'll go with you.
我和你一块去
I'll go too.
我也去
Strange.
奇怪
Seems like the air conditioner
对孩子们来说空调的冷气会不会开得太足了
Seven minutes left.
还有七分钟
It's a nice bronze statue, isn't it?
真是座不错的铜像啊
I heard this is Mr. Schindler's favorite one of his collections.
听说是辛多拉老板最满意的收藏品呢
Oh...
哦
He even went to all that trouble to move it here.
特地搬到这里来
It seems he really likes it.
看来他还真的是很喜欢这东西
It's not that common to find a bronze statue of this kind
在此类铜像中有如此充满斗志的姿态真是罕见
He may think that it's just like himself.
大概跟他自己很像吧
I'm screwed.
糟糕
Hideki, don't play soccer here.
秀树 别在这里踢球
I see.
是
We were a bit out of line, I guess.
好像有点过分了
We were not.
才不会呢
They all look like some bargains.
看上去都是些便宜货
No way!
不会吧
How could they possibly put expensive things
这种地方怎么可能放贵重的东西呢
You got a good point.
说得也是
Tadahashi Kashimura, the development director of "Cocoons",
"茧"的开发负责人坚村忠彬
is a good college friend of mine.
是我大学时代的损友
Thanks to this cooperation,
通过这次的工作
we had a chance to rekindle our old friendship.
让我们重温了过去的友情
Thank you.
谢谢
TMS Shimuzu reports.
以上是由TMS清水为您报道
Where is Mr. Kashimura?
坚村先生在哪里
I'd like to see him.
我想见他
Okay, I'm gonna go find him right now.
是 我马上去找他
Mr. Kudo.
工藤先生
Autograph here, please.
麻烦您签名
Mr. Kudo, please give me an autograph too.
先生 我也要
I'm happy to see that you look well.
你看起来很精神 我也就放心了
You, too.
你也是
(Kashimura's Office)
（坚村办公室）
I gotta get back to the venue right away.
我必须马上赶回会场
So let's get down to business, all right?
你就直接了当的说 如何
The DNA Search Program Hiroki gave to you...
弘树托付给你的DNA探查程序
How much are you going to sell it?
你到底打算要多少钱才肯卖给我
I'm not trying to extort money from you.
我并没打算向你勒索
I just want you to atone for your sins.
我只希望你能赎罪
Hiroki found out that thing.
弘树知道了那件事
The thing that would destroy the Schindler Empire.
那件足以毁灭辛多拉帝国的
Your secret...
你的秘密……
But without Hiroki's ability, you had no way to complete AI.
但是如果不借助弘树的力量人工智能就无法完成
So you pushed Hiroki to work on it, forced him to finish it as soon as possible.
于是你就严厉驱使弘树工作逼迫他早日完成
The morning just after completing AI,
精神上受到极大压迫的弘树
Hiroki, under great mental pressure at that time,
在完成人工智能后的那个早晨
thought he would be killed by you soon.
认为自己马上就会被你杀害
That's why he released Noah's Ark, which can be considered another him,
所以他才把可以说是自己分身的"诺亚方舟"
through the phone line,
通过电话线路释放了出去
and then jumped from the top floor of his apartment.
从公寓的顶楼跳了下来
Soon thereafter,
此后不久
my computer was hacked by the DNA Search Project.
我的电脑遭到了DNA探查程序的数据侵入
It was the work of Noah's Ark, the successor to Hiroki's spirit.
那是继承弘树遗志的"诺亚方舟"所搞的鬼
I think it was a cry from Hiroki's spirit to me.
我觉得这是弘树的魂魄对我所发出的呐喊
I will atone for my sins.
我会赎罪的
I will make all this come to light.
我会将一切公诸于世
I am willing to accept any due punishments.
无论什么样的制裁我都愿意接受
But before that, can I take a look at it?
但在这之前可以让我看一下吗
I mean that DNA Search Project that you said Noah's Ark sent you.
你说的那个"诺亚方舟"传给你的DNA探查程序
Okay.
好吧
This is the one who traveled time and space to modern times,
这就是被超越时空带到现代的
the phantom of London.
伦敦的亡灵
My name is Noah's Ark.
我的名字叫"诺亚方舟"
Director, Mr. Kudo wants to see you.
主任 工藤先生说要见您
Director.
主任
Forgive my rudeness.
打搅了
What happened, Director?
怎么了 主任
So, what is it this time?
这次又有什么花样呢
Now...
接下来
please enjoy the performance
请欣赏今天的特别嘉宾
of our special guest today, Miss Yoko Okino.
冲野洋子小姐为大家的表演
What? Yoko's here too?
什么 洋子也来了吗
I gotta go grab the front-row seat!
得去抢最前面的位子才行
Chiba, block all entrances and exits.
千叶 封锁所有的出入口
Yes, sir.
遵命
Attention, all vehicles on standby!
待命中的车辆注意
Seems like there's a lot of big shots here.
好像来了很多大人物
Yeah.
是的
Deputy Director of Metropolitan Police Department.
警视厅副总监
Industrialist from the financial world.
金融界的实业家
There are also a few council members.
此外还有多位议员
We must be careful.
看来得小心行事啊
Awesome!
好棒哦
Golden Superman Cards!
是黄金超人卡啊
They're already unavailable on the market.
市场上已经停止发售了呀
I want them!
好想要啊
You can exchange these cards for game badges.
可以用参加游戏的胸章交换哦
But I want to play the game too.
可是 我也想玩游戏啊
You still have the chance to play "Cocoons" later,
"茧"以后还可以玩得到
but you know, if you miss
可是这张黄金卡
this golden card this time
现在错过的话
you may never get it again.
以后可能就再也得不到了哦
What should we do?
怎么办
Haibara, we've got them!
灰原 到手啦
Look, this one is for you!
看 还有你的份
Wow, you guys are really something!
哎呀 你们真是了不起
In order to have common topics with you guys,
为了以后的共同话题
maybe it's not a bad idea to participate.
参加一下或许也不坏
Excuse me, got to get by.
对不起 请让一下
Kashimura?
坚村
Take me there, please.
请带我过去
Yes, sir.
是
All right, sorry to keep you waiting.
好 让各位久等了
Please make your way to the venue where "Cocoons" are placed.
大家请到"茧"的会场去
Where's dad and Conan-kun?
爸爸和柯南到哪里去了
Officer!
警官大人
Oh, Mouri.
哦 毛利
You're here too!
你也来啦
I was trying to sober up on the balcony,
我本来在阳台上吹风打算醒一醒酒
but then I saw the police cars.
但是却看到了警车
He is the development director of "Cocoons".
这是"茧"的开发负责人
He was stabbed in the heart and died.
心脏被刺一刀毙命
The murder weapon was taken away.
凶器被带离了现场
The blood was wiped off.
血被擦掉了
The murder weapon is probably something important to the murderer.
凶器可能是凶手珍爱的东西吧
Or perhaps the murderer would be exposed if the weapon was left.
要不就是留下来会让人知道凶手是谁
But then again,
话说回来
why would the development director stay in this kind of basement?
为什么开发负责人会呆在这种地下室呢
Yes.
是的
Director said he couldn't concentrate in a place with a lot of people coming and going.
因为主任说在人出入频繁的地方无法集中精力
That's why he was here alone.
所以一个人在这儿
There's blood on the R, T and J.
RTJ上有血迹
Well, actually, there's another inexplicable thing.
那个  其实还有一件让人费解的事
All the data on the hard drive was destroyed.
硬盘上的数据全都被破坏掉了
Data?
数据
This is the act of rival company's sabotage.
竞争对手公司的破坏行为
But if so, that's too late, isn't it?
这样未免太迟了吧
Because "Cocoons" has already been completed.
因为"茧"已经完成了
When did you get in here, little brat?
这小子什么时候跑进来的
Could the keyboard on the desk be the message he left before he died?
桌上的键盘会不会是死亡讯息
What?
什么
There's blood on the keyboard.
键盘上有血
He probably pressed these keys just before he died.
好像是他在临死之前按下去的
R, T, J.
R T J
JR and JT.
JR跟JT
Tram and cigarette?
电车跟香烟
RTJ.
RTJ
TJR.
TJR
TRJ.
TRJ
JTR.
JTR
London a hundred years ago.
一百年前的伦敦
Could it be?
难道是
Isn't that Conan-kun?
那不是柯南吗
Why is Conan-kun in the game participants' group?
柯南为什么会在游戏参加者的行列里
Here.
拿去吧
It's okay. You can go participate for me.
让给你也没关系
You care about that boy, right?
你不是很在意那孩子的事吗
You're his protector.
作为他的保护者
But Sonoko, you...
可是这样园子你
It's okay. It's okay.
没关系 没关系
I'm not interested at all.
我一点兴趣都没有
All 50 participants are on board.
50位 全员搭乘完毕
Brainwave transmission set.
脑波传动装置 设置完毕
Capsule shells closed.
机舱盖 关闭
Main hardware connecting.
主硬件开始连接
Area code in progress.
输入区域编码
Coupler connecting.
连接联接器
Fine-tuning of coordinate axes in progress.
坐标轴 进行微调
Adjustment of coordinate points has been done.
坐标点调整结束
Locked.
锁定
Screen display. System on.
画面显示 系统启动
Energy setting has been done.
能量设定结束
Game start.
游戏开始
It should be there.
应该存在
In this game,
在这个游戏中
there should be a key to solve this murder mystery.
应该存在解开这起杀人事件之谜的钥匙
Kashimura!
坚村
I heard that Kashimura-san was your old friend.
听说你跟坚村是长久以来的老朋友
Do you know anyone who might want him dead?
知不知道他跟什么人有仇
I thought you were with him,
你不是跟他在一起的吗
that boy with the glasses?
那个戴眼镜的少年
You mean Conan?
你说柯南啊
He was here a while ago,
他刚才还在这里
but after seeing the death message left on the keyboard,
但看到键盘上的死亡讯息后
his face suddenly changed
脸色突然变了
Death message?
死亡讯息
JTR?
JTR
What did you say?
你说什么
Could it be that Conan-kun used the gift I gave him?
难道柯南用了我送给他的礼物了吗
Let's go, Professor.
我们走吧 博士
Wait...wait a minute, Yusaku-kun!
等…等一下 优作
What exactly do these three letters mean?
这三个英文字母是什么意思
This is short for a character who will appear in the game.
这是在游戏中登场的某个人物的简称
That's what Kashimura and I call him.
我和坚村之间都是这样称呼他的
Jack the Ripper?
开膛手杰克
Right.
是的
He was a murderer who actually existed in London at the end of the 19th century,
他是实际存在于19世纪末伦敦的杀人魔
an insane murderer who killed five women with a knife
用刀杀害了5名女性
and caused a great panic in the city of London at that time.
让伦敦全市陷入极度恐慌的疯狂杀人魔
In the end, the London police still failed to arrest him.
伦敦警方到最后还是没能逮捕到他
This serial killer remains a mystery.
这起连续杀人案到现在还是个迷
Judging from Kashimura's death message,
从坚村的死亡讯息中
Conan should have found out that there are clues of the culprit in the game.
柯南大概已经确信游戏中应该有犯人的线索
Mr. Schindler,
辛多拉社长
this is Inspector Megure from the Metropolitan Police Department.
这位是警视厅的目暮警官
Metropolitan Police Department?
警视厅
What do you want from me, officer?
警察找我有什么事
Please suspend the game.
请你暂时中止游戏
Suspend?
中止
Ridiculous.
真是荒唐
Mr. Schindler.
辛多拉社长
Something wrong happened to the system.
系统发生异常
What?
什么
It's out of control.
无法控制
Let me get by.
借过一下
What is it?
什么
Ran!
兰
What are you doing in there?
你在里面干什么
My name is Noah's Ark.
我的名字叫"诺亚方舟"
What?
什么
The game can't be stopped.
游戏已经无法停止
The virtual experience game, "Cocoons"
体验模拟游戏"茧"
has been under my control.
已经被我控制了
What... What is this?
这  这是什么
What is "Noah's Ark"?
什么是"诺亚方舟"
All I know is that it seems to be an artificial intelligence
我只知道好像是只用一年
which grows five human years in a span of one year, right?
就能完成人类费时五年成长的人工智能吧
Right.
没错
It was completed two years ago
那是在两年前
by Hiroki, whom I loved like my own son.
由被我当成亲生儿子般疼爱的弘树所完成的
So I think it must be the same age as Hiroki now.
所以现在应该跟弘树是同样年纪
Noah's Ark.
诺亚方舟
Why do you control the children's game?
你控制孩子们的游戏想干什么
Because I want to
我的目的是想要
give Japan a new life.
让日本这个国家重生
What?
什么
Conan-kun!
柯南
Ran-nee-chan?
小兰姐
Why are you here?
为什么你会在这里
Because I'm worried about you!
因为我担心你啊
Conan-kun!
柯南
Even you guys are here?
连你们也来了
It took us a lot of efforts to get here.
为了到这里来我们可是费了好大劲啊
After all that talk,
说了那么多
it turns out that you want to play this game too.
原来你也很想参加这个游戏啊
Yeah, I do.
是呀
But even though we're under hypnosis now,
不过我们现在虽然处在催眠状态
we don't feel that way.
可是却没有那种感觉
It's like we're dreaming.
好像在做梦似的
We can even move around as we please.
竟然还可以随意走动
But I see just the opposite.
刚好相反
There's no freedom at all.
说什么自由
All our senses of sight,
视觉
sound,
听觉
smell,
嗅觉
taste,
味觉
and touch
触觉
are controlled by the computer.
全都受到电脑的控制
All right, everyone who's experiencing "Cocoons" for the first time.
那么 初次体验"茧"的大家
The game has begun.
游戏开始了
My name is Noah's Ark.
我的名字叫"诺亚方舟"
Nice to meet you.
请多指教
I'm going to show you the demo videos of five different scenarios.
现在我将播放5种场景的演示影像
Please choose one world you want to play in.
请从中选择自己想要玩的世界
But there is one thing to note.
不过有一点要注意
This is not an ordinary video game,
这并不是一个单纯的电视游戏
but a game that relates to your lives.
这可是关系到你们性命的游戏
Our lives?
我们的性命
If all of you are out of the game,
所有人都出局的话
you'll never return to the real world.
你们就无法回到现实世界了
So, you must take this game very seriously.
所以 你们要认真的玩游戏才行
As long as one of you makes it to the end,
只要有一个人能到达终点
you will win.
就算你们赢了
All the kids who are out of the game before will also be able to wake up
在这之前出局的所有孩子也将能苏醒
and go back to the real world.
回到现实的世界
This is the rule of the game I set.
这是我决定的游戏规则
Understand?
明白了吗
What's going on?
这是怎么回事
When all of you are out of the game,
当所有人都出局的时候
I will release a special electromagnetic wave
我就会释放出特殊的电磁波
to destroy your brains.
破坏你们的大脑内部
That is to say, the rebirth of Japan will bet on this game.
也就是说这是一场以日本的重生为赌注的游戏
What does the rebirth of Japan mean?
日本的重生是什么意思
Although you can't hear the sound of the real world here,
虽然大家在这里听不到现实世界的声音
an adult just asked a question.
不过刚才有大人问了个问题
So I'll answer it.
所以我来回答
If you look at yourself,
看到你们的这副德行
you'll see that the son of a dirty politician
想必肮脏的政治家的儿子
will only become another dirty politician,
只会成为肮脏的政治家
the kids of avaricious doctors
满脑子只想着赚钱的医生的孩子
will only end up as such avaricious doctors.
最后也只会变成那种医生
To make Japan a better country,
想让日本变好的话
we must cut off this kind of connection once and for all.
就必须把这样的关系一次性清除干净才行
Stop this nonsense!
不要再胡闹了
You don't have the right to decide human life, do you?
你有玩弄人类生命的权利吗
No, I don't.
我是没有
Just like adults don't have the right to decide Hiroki's life.
就像大人没有权利玩弄弘树的生命一样
All right, the kids have waited too long.
好 孩子们已经等不及了
Almost time to start the game.
差不多该开始游戏了
The first scenario, Vikings.
首先 第一个场景 维京海盗
You will become Vikings who travel to seven seas
你们将成为维京海盗 前往七个海域
and challenge a variety of adventures with a strong will and courage.
用坚强的意志和勇气挑战各种冒险
The second is the Paris-Dakar Rally.
第二个是 巴黎－达喀尔拉力赛
You will participate with world-renowned drivers
和世界著名的车手一起参加
and compete for the championship in this tough rally.
在严酷的比赛中争夺冠军
The third is the Ancient Roman Coliseum.
第三个是 古罗马竞技场
You will be armed with powerful weapons and armors
带上强力的武器和铠甲
and see how great you are in the Roman Empire.
到罗马帝国测试你们的身手
You must defeat the toughest demon warrior.
打倒勇猛的神鬼战士
The fourth is Solomon's Treasures.
第四个是 所罗门的宝藏
You will play jewel hunters
你们将扮演珠宝猎人
and search for Solomon's treasures buried around the world.
寻找埋藏在世界各地的所罗门宝藏
And finally, the fifth is London in the Olden Days.
最后 第五个是旧时代的伦敦
Here you will experience a scary suspense story.
在这里 大家将体验恐怖的悬疑故事
Your target is a serial killer
1888年的伦敦
who appeared in London in 1888
在现实世界
and remains a mystery to this day,
至今仍是未解之谜的连续杀人案件的凶手
Jack the Ripper.
开膛手杰克
Your mission is to bring him to justice.
要靠大家的力量将他绳之以法
As expected,
果然没错
there seems to be a clue here.
这里似乎有什么线索
A clue of the murderer who killed Kashimura.
杀死坚村的凶手的线索
If we're all out of the game,
如果大家都出局的话
are we really going to die?
我们真的会死吗
Why is this happening to us?
为什么我们会遇到这么倒霉的事
It's not like I chose to become my father's child by myself.
人家又不是因为自己想要而成为爸爸的孩子的
I don't think I'll survive.
我可能没办法活下去
Everyone! Please try to make it to the end!
不管是谁 请坚持到最后
Help me!
救救我啊
Pull yourself together, everyone!
大家提起精神来
Don't give up before the game is over.
不能在决出胜负前就认输
That's right!
就是啊
As long as one of us can make it to the end, we'll be fine.
只要有一个人能到终点就可以了
Now let's start to pick the scenario where we think we may have a chance of surviving.
现在大家挑选自己有希望活下去的场景吧
I guess we have no choice but to take on this challenge.
看来只有硬拼了
Moroboshi-kun, which scenario are you going to choose?
诸星 你要选哪个场景
Whatever.
没办法
(Solomon's Treasures)
（所罗门宝藏）
(Paris-Dakar Rally)
（巴黎－达喀尔拉力赛）
(London in the Olden Days)
（旧时代的伦敦）
Are you gonna be with us?
你们也和我们一块吗
Don't get in our way.
别妨碍我们哦
It should be us who say this.
这是我们要说的话才对
All right, all right. No fighting.
好了好了 不要吵架
In each scenario there is a character who will help you.
每个场景都有一个帮助你们的角色
You can count on that person if you need to.
到时可以依靠他
Then, game on!
那么 游戏开始
Alright, let's go.
好 走吧
Okay.
好
How is it going, Professor?
怎么样 博士
"Cocoons" do store a very large amount of energy,
在"茧"中的确储存了非常大的能量
enough to destroy the brains of 50 people.
足以破坏50个人的大脑的能量
I don't have time to waste here.
懒得陪你们耗下去
I'm taking my son back.
我要带儿子回去
I'll take my son back too.
我也要带儿子回去
Sir...
客人
Get out of my way!
让开
It's dangerous! Stop them!
危险 快去阻止他们
Are you all right?
不要紧吧
Did you get hurt?
没受伤吧
No one will be allowed to interfere with the game.
绝不允许任何人妨碍游戏
I just gave them a little electric shock.
刚才只是稍微电击他们一下
Next time, I won't be that gentle.
下次我可不会手软的
Damn, how can he be such a jerk!
可恶 竟然有这种人
But then again, Mr. Schindler...
话说回来 辛多拉社长
How come Hiroki-kun's artificial intelligence
弘树发明的人工智能
could become so out of control?
为什么会变得如此失控
Well, it's because...
这 这是因为
Let me explain.
由我来解释吧
The reason why Hiroki-kun left his father
弘树之所以会离开父亲
and moved to America with his mother
并与母亲一起去美国
is because he couldn't adapt to Japanese school education.
是因为他无法适应日本的学校教育
Hey, Hiroki!
喂 弘树
Because you're weak, I let you rest.
因为你的身体虚弱我才让你休息
But I didn't say you could play on the computer.
但并没有说你可以玩电脑啊
It is said that the rigid educational institution
压抑孩子的个性成长
that inhibits the development of a child's individuality
思想僵硬的教育机关
sees Hiroki as a weird child who is addicted to computers.
据说只把弘树看成一个沉溺于电脑的怪小孩
Not only the educational institution,
不仅是教育机关
even the entire Japan doesn't recognize individuality.
连日本这个国家都不承认个性这种东西
The reason why Hiroki wanted to develop artificial intelligence
弘树之所以想开发人工智能
is because he had experienced this kind of pain.
是因为自己曾经有过这种痛苦的经历
In other words, Hiroki committed suicide
也就是说 日本的重生
before finding a way to give Japan a new life,
是指代替在找到让日本重生的方式前就自杀的弘树
and the artificial intelligence Noah's Ark, inherited his unfinished mission,
而一边逃亡一边继续成长的人工智能"诺亚方舟"
and finally found this specific solution.
找到的具体的解决方式吧
It believes that if it can seize the opportunity of this game presentation
在这个聚集了日本第二三代的游戏发布会上
bringing together the second and third generations of Japan,
若能将"遵循父母所铺的路走就行"
to destroy the social phenomenon of "just following the path laid down by your parents",
这种社会现象加以破坏的话
Japan will change.
日本就会改变
But Mr. Kudo, why do you know that?
工藤先生 为什么你连这些事情都知道
In fact, over the past year,
其实这一年来
I have been serving as the detective, and Kashimura had been my client.
我和坚村是保持着侦探和委托人之间的关系
Detective?
侦…侦探
What did he ask you to investigate?
他委托你调查什么事
He asked me to investigate Hiroki-kun's suicide again.
他要我再调查一次关于弘树的自杀事件
Are you saying that Hiroki didn't commit suicide, but got killed by someone else?
你是说弘树不是自杀而是他杀吗
No.
不
Judging from that situation, it should be a suicide.
以那种情况来说应该是自杀
But what drove Hiroki-kun to his death?
究竟是什么原因逼弘树走上了绝路
Kashimura asked me to investigate.
坚村委托我调查
What was the relationship between Kashimura-san and Hiroki-kun?
坚村先生和弘树是什么关系
Kashimura was Hiroki-kun's father.
坚村是弘树的父亲
Am I right?
对吧
Hiroki-kun parted from him when he was a child.
从小就跟他分开的弘树
He never thought his son would die in that way.
竟然以那种方式死去
Kashimura had been blaming himself for that.
坚村为此一直在深深地自责
Conan-kun and the others have entered the Whitchapel area.
柯南他们进入白教堂地区了
Are we going in here?
要进这里面去吗
Let's go.
走吧
Hurry up, please.
请快点走啦
What are you doing?
你干什么啊
Because you're moving too slow, Genta-kun!
因为元太你走太慢啦
Now we're at the city of flog, London.
这就是雾都伦敦
It's not so much romantic as spooky.
与其说浪漫不如说是诡异
Even the air feels dirty.
好像连空气都很脏
And it stinks.
还有味道呢
London's fog
伦敦的雾
is not just a clean substance condensed from water vapor,
并非只是由水蒸气凝结而成的干净物质
but a smog combining fog and soot
是煤和石油燃烧所产生的烟尘
generated by burning coal and oil.
与雾结合而成的烟雾
So there is already smog in this era.
原来在这个时代就已经有烟雾啦
Jack the Ripper!
开膛手杰克
Hey, Conan!
喂 柯南
Stop!
住手
I won't let you escape!
我不会让你逃走的
It hurts!
好痛
Are you okay, Conan-kun?
你没事吧 柯南
It seems that Professor Agasa's invention
看来阿笠博士的发明
can not be used in the game world.
无法在游戏世界里使用
Indeed.
是啊
Although the antenna can still be retracted,
虽然这眼镜的天线还可以伸缩
it's just an ordinary pair of glasses,
但也只是一副普通的眼镜
and this is also just an ordinary watch.
这也只是一只普通的手表
Oh my god!
糟了
It's Jack the Ripper!
开膛手杰克出现啦
What is he saying?
他在说什么
Seems like he's speaking English.
这好像是英语啊
Call the police!
快叫警察来
Please switch to Japanese.
请转成日语
Yes, sir.
是
What's going on?
怎么了 发生什么事了
There's another victim.
又有牺牲者了
This is already the third victim.
这已经是第三个人了
Ah, they speaks Japanese now!
啊 变成日语了
It's exactly like the real world.
简直就像是真实的世界
It's not just what we see and hear.
不仅是看到的听到的
Even the cold air seems real.
就连寒冷的空气都像是真的
Even the pain in my feet feels real.
连我的脚疼都是真的
Hey, get out of the way!
喂 让开 让开
Stand back, please.
请退后
Hey, call Inspector Lestrade right away.
喂 马上联络雷斯垂德警官
Yes, sir.
是
Inspector Lestrade?
雷斯垂德警官
Professor, can we talk to them?
博士 可以和他们通话吗
I'll try.
我试试看吧
Since you're in charge of developing this game.
工藤先生既然负责策划这个游戏
You should know how to win this game, right?
应该知道如何攻关吧
I do.
是的
A long as I can talk with them,
只要能联络
I'll give instructions to help them.
我就可以给予指示帮助他们
Then this problem can be solved.
这样事情就好解决了啊
We'll definitely win this game!
这场游戏赢定了
But...
但是
If Noah's Ark can predict things that haven't happened yet...
如果"诺亚方舟"能够预测还未发生的情况的话
Professor, the rest is up to you.
博士 剩下的就拜托你了
I gotta go to the scene.
我到现场去
I see.
我知道了
It just told us to catch the killer, that's all.
真是的 说要我们抓住凶手什么的
But where are we going to find him?
要到哪里去找啊
I guess we'll have to wait until dawn.
看来只有等到天亮了
It's cold.
好冷
Put this on.
穿上这个吧
Is it okay?
可以吗
So warm!
好温暖哦
Haibara-san, please put on this coat.
灰原 穿上外套吧
Oh, thank you.
哎呀 谢谢你
You're welcome.
不客气
Put this on.
你穿这个吧
But what about you, Genta-kun?
那么 元太你
It's okay. The cold doesn't bother me.
我很怕热 没关系的
Thank you.
谢谢
Can you hear me, Conan-kun?
听得到吗 柯南
This is Agasa.
我是阿笠
I can hear you, Professor.
我听得到 博士
Listen.
听好了
In this game, if you get hurt or get caught by the police,
在这一关当中只要受伤或是被警察捉住
you are out.
就算出局了哦
Your current location is
你们现在的位置是
near the Whitechapel area in East End.
伊斯特威多的白教堂附近
If you want to find the character who can help you...
从那里到能帮助你们的角色的所在地点
What's wrong?
怎么了
What happened, Professor?
怎么了 博士
I can't hear you!
听不见啊
Catch me!
抓住我
Conan, hold on!
柯南 加油
It was so dangerous!
好危险啊
It seems that you haven't understood that
看来你们还没搞清楚啊
this game is totally under my control.
这个游戏全都由我掌控
Don't try to cheat. It's useless.
想投机取巧是没有用的
I'll let you listen to the sound over there.
我让你们听听那边的声音好了
You can enjoy the cries of pain from your children.
好好享受孩子们痛苦的呼喊吧
How can there be such a nasty computer?
怎么会有如此性格恶劣的电脑
We can't hear Professor's voice now.
博士的声音听不见了
Looks like Noah's Ark has cut our communication with outside.
看来通讯被"诺亚方舟"切断了
Then, how can we find the character who can help us?
那么 我们怎样才能找到能帮助我们的角色呢
Didn't the police tell us the answer?
这个 刚才警察不是已经说了吗
Call Inspector Lestrade.
联络雷斯垂德警官
Could he be the same Inspector Lestrade in the novel?
难道是指那个故事中出现的雷斯垂德警官吗
But he's just a fictional character in Conan Doyle's novel, isn't he?
可是 那是出现在柯南道尔小说中的人物吧
It is possible that
这个游戏
this game is a world where reality and fiction are integrated together.
可能是个将现实与小说融合在一起的世界
So the person who can help us is...
那帮助我们的人是
Yeah, he should exist in this world.
啊 他应该是存在于这个世界的
That Sherlock Holmes.
那位夏洛克福尔摩斯
Really? With Sherlock Holmes on our side,
真的吗 有福尔摩斯的话
it's like we have the help of 100 people.
就等于多了100人的力量啊
We'll definitely win this round!
这一局我们赢定了
Let's get going. Go to Baker Street!
我们快走吧 去贝克街
Good, as long as they meet Holmes...
好啊 只要能见到福尔摩斯
But it's really a long way from the Whitechapel area to Baker Street.
不过 从白教堂地区到贝克街很远啊
Hey, don't you think that clock is a bit strange?
喂 你不觉得那个钟有点怪吗
Its minute hand is going backwards.
分针倒回去了
Ah, it went backwards again.
啊 又倒回去了
50 changed to 49,
从50分到49分
and then changed to 48.
然后又是48分
I see.
我知道了
That's the number of kids playing the game.
那是参加游戏的小孩人数
So two minutes backwards means...
倒转两分钟的意思就是指
two people are already out of the game in other scenarios?
有两个人已经在别的场景中出局了
Yasuhiro!
康裕
Two people were eliminated in the Vikings scenario.
在"海盗"关中有两个人被淘汰
Miyuki...
朋之
Mirekoga...
峰…峰子她
Now two people were eliminated in the Ancient Roman Coliseum.
这次是在"古罗马竞技场"有两个人被淘汰
Faster.
再快一点
Get out of the game faster.
再快一点出局吧
If those kids find out the real identity of Jack the Ripper,
如果被孩子们找到开膛手杰克的真正身份
I'm done.
我就完了
Three more eliminated in Solomon's Treasures.
在"所罗门"有三个人被淘汰
43 people left, right?
剩下43个人是吧
I heard in the alley of Miter Street.
在玛伊塔街的巷子里
there was another one killed.
听说又有人被杀了
Two cases within one hour.
一小时内发生了两起
That's the fourth one.
这是第四起了
What a scary world.
真是可怕的世界
It's horrible.
好恐怖哦
We've come to a scary time.
我们来到了一个可怕的时代啊
Although the end of the 19th century in London
世纪末的伦敦虽说是
was considered to be the last era of prosperity of the British Empire,
大英帝国最后的一个繁荣时代
actually, it was an era of the widest wealth gap,
但实际上却是一个贫富差距非常大
rampant crimes,
犯罪猖獗
and depravity of the people.
人心堕落的时代
It reminded me that Shinichi once said,
这么说来 倒是听新一说过
if we referred to Sherlock Holmes as the light of the times,
如果把夏洛克福尔摩斯比喻为时代之光的话
then Jack the Ripper was the shadow of darkness.
那么开膛手杰克就是黑暗的影子
Then let's go find the light of the times.
那我们快朝时代之光那儿赶去吧
We're almost at Baker Street.
贝克街快到了哦
Watch out for Jack the Ripper!
小心开膛手杰克哦
He's waiting for you on the road at night.
他在夜晚的路上等着你哟
If you don't want to die,
如果不想死的话
what should you do?
该怎么办才好呢
You must be covered in blood too.
你也得浑身浴血才行
What does that mean?
这是什么意思
It means you must kill your rival before he kills you, right?
是在被干掉之前先把对方干掉吧
Covered in blood?
浑身浴血
There's a metal detector at venue's entrance.
会场入口有金属探测器
How did the culprit bring the murder weapon in?
犯人是如何把凶器带进来的呢
We were not.
才不会呢
They all look like some bargains.
看上去都是些便宜货
No way!
不会吧
How could they possibly put expensive things in this kind of place?
这种地方怎么可能放昂贵的东西呢
(Baker Street) 221B.
（贝克街） 221号B
This is the place, right?
是这里吧
So this is where that Sherlock Holmes lives?
那位夏洛克福尔摩斯就住在这里吗
This is the apartment he rented with Dr. Watson.
这是他和华生大夫一起租的公寓
Who is it this late?
这么晚了 是哪位
I... I'm Ran Mouri.
我 我叫毛利兰
I came for Mr. Holmes.
我想见福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Holmes and Dr. Watson are away on a case.
福尔摩斯先生和华生大夫出去办案了不在家
On a case?
出去办案
Oh, yes.
是啊
To a village called Dartmoor.
到一个叫达特莫尔的乡村去了
If you don't mind, what's the date?
对不起 今天是几月几日
September 30th.
9月30日
September 30th, Dartmoor...
9月30日 达特莫尔
Oh, I remember.
想起来了
It's the Hound of the Baskervilles case.
是"巴斯克维尔猎犬"案件
Yeah, both of them left London at this time.
是啊 这正是两人都离开伦敦的时候
Hey, Professor.
喂 博士
What exactly is going on?
到底是怎么回事啊
Sorry to bother you.
对不起
Let me see the video around the time of the crime, please.
请让我看一下犯罪时间前后的录像
Got it.
我知道了
Yes.
是
What's going on?
怎么了
Seems like we underestimated Noah's Ark before.
我们似乎太小看"诺亚方舟"了
Neither Holmes nor Watson was in Baker Street.
福尔摩斯和华生都不在贝克街
So he really predicted it.
果然被他先猜到了
There was even a strange accordion-wielding character that I didn't put in.
连我没有编入的奇怪的手风琴角色都出现了
Things are not looking good.
前景不妙啊
Hey, what is the plot that you originally planned?
喂 优作所设想的游戏到底是什么样的情节
The player and Sherlock Holmes would work together
玩家和夏洛克福尔摩斯携手合作
to find out the real identity of Jack the Ripper.
找出开膛手杰克的真实身份
And they would finally found out that the monstrous serial killer
最后发现连续杀人恶魔
was an aristocrat with a terminal illness.
是一个患了绝症的贵族
I've got an even better ending for you.
我帮你准备了更加精彩的结局
Damn it, if the kids win,
可恶 如果孩子们赢了
I swear I'll throw this computer into a large landfill!
我就要把你这种电脑扔到大型垃圾回收场
Try you best, Shinichi!
加油 新一
It's you kids, right?
就是你们
Two weeks ago,
在两个礼拜前
you helped Mr. Holmes solve the case, didn't you?
帮助福尔摩斯先生破案立了大功吧
Come on in, please.
来吧 快请进来吧
I'll get you some hot milk tea.
我去倒些热奶茶给你们喝
Seems like she has mistaken us for someone else.
好像把我们误认为是谁了
I see.
知道了
She must have confused us with the Baker Street Irregulars.
她把我们与"贝克街侦探小队"搞混了
What's that?
那是什么
It's a group of homeless kids hired by Sherlock Holmes.
福尔摩斯雇佣的流浪小孩们
They go into places where adults can't go to gather information.
他们专门潜入大人进不去的地方收集情报
All of them were brave kids.
是一群勇敢的孩子
So they're our Detective Boys' predecessors?
也就是我们少年侦探团的前辈
That's right.
没错
They finally got into the apartment.
他们总算进入公寓了
Awesome!
好棒啊
It's exactly like what I saw on TV.
跟在电视上看到的完全一样啊
I'm so excited!
好激动哦
Shinichi would definitely be envious if he knew this.
要是新一知道的话一定会很羡慕吧
He's so like Shinichi.
跟新一好像
Oops, he's so like Sherlock Holmes.
哎呀 跟福尔摩斯先生好像啊
He always thinks in this position!
他一直是以这种姿势想问题的哦
So that's it.
什么啊
He's just imitating Sherlock Holmes.
原来是在模仿福尔摩斯啊
Then, before I'm done making tea,
那在我泡完茶之前
you kids can enjoy yourself here.
你们先放松休息吧
Thank you.
谢谢你
Hey, this person in this photo really looks like someone.
喂 这张照片好像某个人哦
Although he has hair, everyone can see that he's Professor Agasa.
虽然有头发 明明是阿笠博士嘛
They must be Mr. Holmes and Dr. Watson, right?
这是福尔摩斯和华生大夫吧
Dad and Professor...
老爸和博士
Can you two be more childish?
还真是会玩
Hey, we don't have time to waste here, right?
喂 我们没时间在这磨蹭吧
But, Moroboshi-kun,
但是诸星
what should we do now?
我们该怎么做呢
That four-eyed boy must know.
那个戴眼镜的一定知道
Since he's Sherlock Holmes,
既然是福尔摩斯
he must have collected a lot of information about Jack the Ripper.
那他一定收集了很多关于开膛手杰克的资料
Then, let's split up and find out.
那么 大家分头来找找看吧
Okay, I'll look over here.
好 那我找这边
But how can we find out? These are all English books.
可是找归找全都是英文啊
This one.
这个
Initial investigation for crime.
有关犯罪的初步调查
Oh my god!
好厉害
I'm a genius?
我是天才吗
I can read English!
我读得懂英文耶
Me too.
我也是
It seems that the player is programmed to read English.
看来玩家被设定为看得懂英文了
If so, I hope I can stay in the game forever!
既然这样我好想一直呆在游戏里啊
What are you talking about, Genta-kun?
你在说什么啊 元太
If this continues, we'll be eliminated and die!
这样下去我们会被淘汰出局死掉的啦
I'm just kidding.
开玩笑啦  玩笑
What a dirty ball!
好脏的球
This is...
这 这是
Hey, Emouri!
喂 江守
This is soccer from a hundred years ago!
这是一百年前的足球啊
Wow, really!
哇 真的是
I found it. Is it this one?
有了 是不是这个
An analysis of Jack the Ripper.
关于开膛手杰克的调查
The latest case took place on
最近一次发生的案件
September 8th.
9月8日
The second victim was Honey Charleston,
第二个受害者是哈妮查理斯特
a 41-year-old female who lived alone.
独居 41岁的女性
The location where the body was found was
发现尸体的地点是
a vacant lot next to St. Mary's Church in the Whitechapel area.
白教堂地区圣玛丽教堂旁边的空地
There were two rings of different sizes left at the scene.
犯罪现场遗留有两枚不同尺寸的戒指
Rings of different sizes?
不同尺寸的戒指
Judging from the fact that he caused such tremendous social unrest,
让伦敦陷入极度恐慌的开膛手杰克
I am sure that Jack the Ripper, who has plunged London into extreme panic,
从他引发的前所未有的社会不安这点来看
must be connected with the head of evil, Professor Moriarty,
我可以确信与邪恶之首莫里亚蒂教授有关联
Professor Moriarty?
莫里亚蒂教授
Even this guy is in the game?
连这家伙都在游戏中登场吗
Who is this guy?
那家伙是谁啊
Don't forget about us, alright? We don't understand.
别自顾自说 我们可不明白啊
He's Holmes' arch-enemy.
他是福尔摩斯的宿敌
He controls the dark forces of London.
控制着伦敦的黑暗势力
It is said that he has a great influence on the whole Europe.
据说他对整个欧洲都有着很大的影响力
The Napoleon in the criminal world.
犯罪界的拿破仑
But, although Professor Moriarty is the one who manipulates behind the scenes,
但是莫里亚蒂教授虽在背后操纵
he rarely reveals his whereabouts.
却是个很少暴露行踪的人物
How can we catch him?
怎样才能抓到他呢
Since we can't find the professor,
既然教授不露身影
we gotta go find someone related to him.
那我们就去找跟他有关的人好了
Colonel Sebastian Moran.
去找塞巴斯蒂恩莫兰上校
Indeed.
对啊
Colonel Moran, the professor's top general.
教授的心腹大将莫兰上校
But where is he?
可是他在哪儿
He must be...
他一定是在
Holmes' notes say
福尔摩斯的笔记上写着
he frequents
他时常出现在
the bridge club downtown.
市中心的桥牌俱乐部
Because he's the second most dangerous man in London.
因为他是伦敦第二号的危险人物
We must be careful with him.
接触时要小心行事
Conan-kun, you really know a lot.
柯南 你知道好多哦
Because Shinichi-san often told me about this.
因为我也经常听新一哥哥讲
So that's it? I knew it.
什么嘛 果然是这样啊
But who knew that the words of that nagging Sherlock Holmes fan
不过 没想到那个缠人的福尔摩斯迷所说的话
could be useful this time?
这次倒还真派上了大用场
There is no need to say the word "nagging".
"缠人"这词儿就免了吧
Wow, it's a real gun!
哇 是真枪耶
Put it back, Genta.
放回去 元太
But aren't we going to meet a dangerous guy?
可是我们不是要去见危险的家伙吗
A weapon you don't know how to use well won't help.
还没用惯的武器是派不上用场的
It'll only cause trouble!
只会惹出麻烦
Put it back!
快放回去
Looks like you're the scarier one.
你 还是你比较可怕
Then, let's get going before it's too late.
那么 我们赶快趁早走吧
Hey, Moroboshi!
喂 诸星
We gotta take our life in our own hands.
自己的命要自己来保护
There are 30 people left.
还剩下30人
There's a lot of people out.
少了很多人啊
I guess there should be someone
我们几个人之中
among us about to be out too, right?
也快有人要被淘汰了吧
Don't jinx it, okay?
别说不吉利的话
Toru!
小彻
Emi!
绘美
Takuya!
卓也
(Bridge Club)
桥牌俱乐部
Wait for me here, everyone.
那么 大伙在这儿等我
I'll go in through the back door and see what's going on inside.
我从后门溜进去看看里面的情况
Be careful.
小心点
One card.
一张
I'll give two.
我两张
It's Colonel Moran.
是莫兰上校
The monkey?
那只猴子
How is it, four eyes?
怎么样 眼镜
What are you doing here?
你们怎么也进来了
You want to be the hero alone? I won't let you.
想一个人独占功劳 门都没有
Straight.
顺子
I'm sorry.
不好意思
Flush.
同花
What?
什么
Looks like I'm pretty lucky tonight.
今晚运气似乎不错啊
Damn it!
可恶
So Moran is pretty good at poker?
莫兰那家伙牌技很好吗
He's cheating.
他在出老千
How do you know that?
你看得出来吗
That monkey over there
那边的猴子
is telling Colonel Moran his opponent's cards.
正在把对方的牌告诉莫兰上校
Right hand means heart or spade.
红心 黑桃的话就用右手
Left hand means diamond, or club.
方块 草花的话则用左手
It will eat berries based on card's color and number.
颜色跟数字是多少它就吃几颗同样颜色的果实
If it's a three of spade,
如果是黑桃三的话
it will take three black berries with his right hand to eat.
它就用右手拿三颗黑色果实来吃
A crafty cheater!
真是个卑鄙的家伙
Huh?
奇怪
What's wrong with that seat?
那个座位是怎么回事
Why did they put such things there?
为什么会放那种东西
He cheated!
他出老千
Moran cheated.
莫兰这家伙出老千
Watch your mouth, kid.
小鬼 注意你讲话的口气
Do you have proof that I cheated?
你有我出老千的证据吗
Of course I do.
当然有
That monkey is your friend.
那只猴子跟你很要好
Right?
对吧
What?
什么
It was watching this guy's cards.
看着大叔的牌
If it's a three of spade,
如果是黑桃三的话
it will take three black berries with its right hand to eat.
它就用右手拿三颗黑色果实吃
If it's a five of diamond,
如果是方块五的话
it will take five red berries with its left hand to eat.
它就用左手拿五颗红果实吃
Moran, you're tricky!
莫兰 你太卑鄙了
You fell for it because you are too stupid.
是你自己要上当的
What did you say?
你说什么
You'd better save the fight for later.
你们的架等一下再吵吧
Where's Professor Moriarty?
莫里亚蒂教授在哪儿
How do you know him, brat?
小鬼 你怎么会知道他的
Don't move!
别动
Catch this brat!
给我把小鬼都抓起来
You little brat!
你这小鬼
Are you okay, Conan-kun?
没事吧 柯南
I'm here to help, Conan!
我来帮忙了 柯南
I've knocked one down!
打倒一个
This is awful.
喂 这下糟了
Now all of us are out!
这不是等于全体都出动了吗
Watch out, Conan-kun!
危险 柯南
Kikukawa-kun!
菊川
Hey, hang in there!
喂 振作一点
I've been knocked down!
我被打倒了
You saved me, now I returned the favor.
这样我就还了你救我的人情了
Hey.
喂
Kikukawa...
菊川
Seiichiro!
清一郎
Ayumi-chan, are you okay?
步美 你没事吧
Thank you, Mitsuhiko-kun.
谢谢你 光彦
It's okay.
哪里
Mitsuhiko-kun!
光彦
Ayumi-chan, seems like we're going to be eliminated.
步美 我们好像出局了
Conan-kun, please bring us all back to life!
柯南 你一定要让我们都复活哦
Ayumi! Mitsuhiko!
步美 光彦
Damn!
糟了
If this continues, everyone will be out!
再这样下去所有的人都会出局
SH...
S H
Sherlock Holmes.
夏洛克福尔摩斯
Conan! Watch out!
柯南 危险
Genta!
元太
I'm out.
我出局了啊
Conan, you must catch that Jack the Ripper.
柯南 你一定要抓住开膛手杰克啊
Game over.
游戏到此结束
I was planning to catch you and then ask you who you work for,
本来打算抓住你们后再逼问你们是谁的手下
but now that there is no need to ask.
不过现在看来没有必要了
Because this gun belongs to Holmes.
因为这把枪是福尔摩斯的
Damn, what to do?
可恶 该怎么办才好
What should I do?
该怎么办
The thing in that man's hands...
那男人拿的是
I remember it was...
我记得好像是
the wine on that seat.
放在那个座位上的红酒
I see!
原来如此
So that's what happened!
原来是这么回事
Okay then, who should I start with?
好 从谁先开始呢
You little bastard!
小鬼
If you shoot, this bottle of wine will be broken!
要是开枪的话这瓶红酒就要被打破哦
What do you mean by that?
你这是什么意思
The empty seat at the table where you were playing cards,
你们刚才打牌的那张桌子上的空位子
that specially decorated chair,
特别装饰过的椅子
and the wine and glass prepared for the upcoming person
以及为即将到来的某人准备的酒杯和红酒
told me one thing, that is, that upcoming person
由此便可以推理出将要到来的人
must be Professor Moriarty.
肯定是莫里亚蒂教授了
Unfortunately, you're wrong.
很可惜 你这推理错了
Then shoot,
那你就开枪吧
if it's okay to make the professor's wine broken.
即使教授的红酒被打破也没关系的话
Damn it!
可恶
Conan-kun.
柯南
Mr. Moriarty wants to see you.
莫里亚蒂大人说要见你们各位
Professor Moriarty?
莫里亚蒂教授
He's waiting for you in the carriage.
他在马车上等你们
This way, please.
请往这边走
Please wait.
请等一下
Are you trying to disobey Mr. Moriarty?
你想违抗莫里亚蒂大人吗
I brought them here.
我将他们带来了
Well done.
辛苦你了
All right, little kid.
好 小弟弟
Give me that bottle of wine.
把那瓶红酒交给我吧
Yes, sir.
好的
This scent...
这股香味是
You have the guts to compete with Colonel Moran.
你能和莫兰上校互相较量
As befits the disciple of Sherlock Holmes.
不愧是福尔摩斯的弟子
What do you want from me?
那你们找我有什么事
If you don't mind, are you Professor Moriarty?
大叔 你是莫里亚蒂教授
Of course I am.
当然
Is that so?
是吗
You're testing us in this way, aren't you?
你是用这种方式来试探我们吧
What do you mean?
你这是什么意思
You can drop the act.
不要再演戏了
You're not Professor Moriarty, right?
大叔你不是莫里亚蒂教授吧
What are you talking about, Conan-kun?
你在说什么 柯南
Because the real Professor Moriarty
因为真正的莫里亚蒂教授
is this one.
在这里
How come...
这怎么……
Are you serious?
真的假的
Everything he said was spoken through your ventriloquism, right?
声音全都是教授用腹语讲的 对吧
I didn't think you'd see through that.
没想到连这点都被你看穿
How did you know?
你是怎么知道的
Because Colonel Moran said "please wait" to you.
因为刚才莫兰上校对大叔说"请等一下"
I see.
是啊
Colonel Moran only uses honorific terms with Professor Moriarty.
莫兰上校只会对莫里亚蒂教授使用敬语
Is that all?
只有这点而已吗
There's one more thing.
还有一点
I've heard that Professor Moriarty
我听说莫里亚蒂教授
is a fashionable elderly man who loves to use natural vanilla cologne.
是个爱使用天然香草古龙水的时髦老人
Did you smell it when you were returning his wine?
你是在还他红酒时闻到这股味道的是吗
Beautiful.
真漂亮
You're totally a mini Sherlock Holmes.
简直像看到了一个迷你福尔摩斯一样
But then again,
话说回来
what do you want with me?
你们找我有什么事
Jack the Ripper
开膛手杰克
is the guy you put on the streets
是教授为了让伦敦成为恐怖之都
to make London a city of terror, right?
而派到街头上的人 对吧
You're only half right.
你只说对了一半
Jack the Ripper is a vagrant I picked up in the slums.
开膛手杰克是我在贫民窟捡到的流浪儿
Although he was just a homeless vagrant who had been abandoned by his mother,
他虽然是个被母亲抛弃而流浪街头的流浪儿
I sensed his talent right away.
可是我一眼就感觉到了他的才能
The talent to become a criminal.
成为罪犯的才能
I trained him to become a top-class killer.
是我把他培养成一流杀手的
Why did he kill innocent women?
为什么要杀害无辜的女性呢
The Ripper has become a murderous monster beyond my imagination.
开膛手变成了超乎我想象的杀人恶魔
All this series of cases is the result of the kid's craziness.
这一连串的案件都是因为那孩子发狂的结果
If you want to deal with Jack the Ripper,
如果你们想要对付开膛手杰克的话
I will assist you.
那我也来协助你们好了
Assist?
协助
Though Jack the Ripper has gone crazy,
虽然开膛手杰克已经开始发狂
I think if I give him an order to kill someone, he'll still obey.
不过要是我下达杀人指令的话他应该还是会遵守的
All you have to do is get there first and wait for him.
你们只要先到一步等他就可以了
What will you do?
要怎么做
I'll put a message in tomorrow's Sunday Times billboard
我会在明天的"周日时报"的广告上
for him to read.
刊登消息给他
Who are you going to order him to kill?
你要命令他杀谁
You'll know when you read tomorrow's paper.
看明天的报纸就知道了
Hey, do you really believe this old guy's words?
喂 你真的相信这个老头说的话吗
I'll take a chance.
赌赌看吧
Good luck to you.
祝你们好运
Be careful with Reichenbach Falls in three years.
请当心三年后的莱辛巴赫瀑布
What's Reichenbach?
莱辛巴赫是什么
Three years later, Professor Moriarty
莫里亚蒂教授三年后
faced off with Holmes
会在瑞士的莱辛巴赫瀑布
at Reichenbach Falls in Switzerland.
与福尔摩斯展开对决
Both of them fell into the waterfall.
两个人都掉进了瀑布里
Although Holmes miraculously survived,
虽然福尔摩斯那时候奇迹般地生还
Professor Moriarty died there.
而莫里亚蒂教授却死在那里了
Why would I warn him to be careful?
为什么我会提醒他当心呢
I probably like this bad guy as much as I like Holmes.
我大概和喜欢福尔摩斯一样也很喜欢这个坏蛋吧
Feel so familiar. I remember at that time...
这么说来那个时候
Actually, I also like Professor Moriarty very much.
我其实也很喜欢莫里亚蒂教授的
Of course I only like this guy in the world of fiction.
不过这只限于小说的世界里
When they dueled in Holmes' apartment,
两个人在福尔摩斯的公寓里决斗时
my heart beat really fast.
我真的好紧张啊
I really like what Holmes said at that time.
我很喜欢福尔摩斯当时所说的一句话
Do you know what it is?
你知道是什么吗
No, I don't.
不知道
That is...
那就是
What exactly did Shinichi say?
新一到底说什么了
It was a rare opportunity for us to date,
难得跟他约会
but Shinichi just kept talking about Sherlock Holmes.
新一却一直在说福尔摩斯的事
That's why I didn't even concentrate on his words.
所以我根本没有专心听
Conan-kun.
柯南
What is it?
什么事
Nothing.
没什么
I'm so stupid.
我真傻
How can Conan-kun possibly know about it?
就算是问柯南他也不可能知道嘛
Hey, four eyes.
喂 眼镜
I'm sorry.
对不起
Because of our recklessness,
因为我们的鲁莽
we got four people out of the game.
害得那四人出局了
It's no use regretting what has already happened.
已经过去的事即使后悔也没用了
You guys can think this way,
你们会这么想已经可以算是
it means you've already grown up a lot.
前进了一大步了
That's right.
没错
What's important is what we do next.
重要的是接下来要怎么行动
For all our sakes, let's try our best together.
为了大家 我们一起加油吧
(Whitechapel Area)
白教堂地区
Here is the scene where the body
这里是第二个受害者
of the second victim, Honey Charleston, was found.
哈妮查理斯特的遗体被发现的现场
The parent-child bazaar will be held again on the second Saturday in October.
十月在第二个周六举办亲子慈善义卖会
On the second Saturday?
第二个周六
I remember the date that Honey Charleston was killed is...
我记得哈妮查理斯特被杀害的日子好像是
September 8th, Saturday.
9月8日 星期六
Sorry to keep you waiting.
久等了
You're so slow. Where have you been?
你好慢啊 跑到哪里去了
Just went to have a little bit adventure on the street.
我到街上稍微探了一下险
You're so relaxed.
真是悠闲啊
Today is the day of the duel.
今天可是决战的日子
Jack the Ripper is back.
开膛手杰克又出现啦
There are two victims this time!
这次有两个受害者
One for me, please.
请给我一份
Okay.
好
Oh, no. I don't have pounds.
糟了 没有英国的钱
80 yen.
80日元
Ah, really?
啊 是吗
It's really convenient.
真是方便
Here it is.
在这里
Clean up the stage of the opera house tonight.
今晚去清扫歌剧院的舞台
M to J.
M给J的消息
Moriarty to Jack the Ripper.
莫里亚蒂给开膛手杰克
Clean up the stage of the opera house.
清扫歌剧院的舞台
Is that an order?
这就是指令吗
Maybe this means he'll murder an actor performing on stage.
如果意思是要他去谋杀舞台上表演的演员的话
There it is.
有了
Triumph Public Performance.
凯旋公演
The star of the Wallosa Royal Opera.
华露沙皇家歌剧院的明星
Irene Adler.
艾琳艾德勒
Professor Moriarty.
莫里亚蒂教授
This villain has gone too far.
这个坏蛋太过分了
Who is Irene Adler?
艾琳艾德勒是谁
It is said that she was the only woman Holmes ever loved in his life.
据说是福尔摩斯一生中唯一爱过的女人
That means he's going to murder the woman Holmes loves.
也就是把福尔摩斯所爱的人作为杀害的目标
00:06.
0点6分
That means...
这么说来
All participants in the other scenarios are out.
其他场景的人全都出局了
That is to say, the six of us are responsible for all of their lives.
也就是说我们六个人肩负着所有人的性命
(Opera Theater)
歌剧剧场
Hey!
喂
Unauthorized people are not allowed in here.
这里除了相关人员一律不得进入
We are friends of Irene Adler.
我们是艾琳艾德勒的朋友
We want to give her some encouragement before she goes on stage.
想在登场前给她鼓励
Oh, you're her friends.
哦 是她的朋友啊
Yes, may I know where the lounge is?
是的 请问休息室在哪里
It's the last room with the poster at the end of the hall.
就在最里面贴有海报的房间
This is the room, right? I'm curious what kind of person she is.
是这里吧 不知是怎样的一个人
I'm so nervous.
好紧张啊
Since she's made by dad,
老爸做的角色
and also the woman Holmes loves...
然后又是福尔摩斯所爱的女人的话
Please come in.
请进
Sorry to bother you.
打搅了
Shinichi's mother?
新一的妈妈
I knew it.
不出所料
How rude you are! I'm still single.
真是没礼貌 我还是单身呢
After a divorce, to be exact.
确切的说是离婚后恢复单身
These are flowers from Sherlock Holmes.
这是福尔摩斯送给你的花
Ah, thank you.
啊 谢谢
Where's Holmes?
福尔摩斯人呢
He was looking forward to the show tonight.
他本来很期待今晚的演出
But he was out investigating a case, he couldn't come.
因为出去调查案件了 所以没法来
Really? What a pity.
是吗  真可惜
Please cancel the show tonight.
请取消今晚的表演
Oh...
咦
Holmes' arch enemy.
福尔摩斯的宿敌
Professor Moriarty sent an assassin to kill you.
莫里亚蒂教授派杀手来杀你了
Why did he want to kill me?
为什么要杀我
Because he wanted to see
因为他想看到
Holmes's pained look after losing you.
福尔摩斯失去你之后悲伤的表情
I also wanted to see
我也想看看
how much Holmes would grieve for me?
福尔摩斯究竟会为我悲伤到什么程度
Do you really not care
你真的无所谓吗
about being the fifth victim of Jack the Ripper?
成为开膛手杰克的第五个牺牲者
You will protect me, won't you?
大家会保护我的 不是吗
In place of Holmes.
代替福尔摩斯
This woman must have a lot of nerve.
这女人胆子还真大啊
Yeah, that's so like her.
就是啊 她就是这种性格
Die a beautiful death.
美丽的死去吧
Irene Adler.
艾琳艾德勒
Where is he hiding?
那家伙躲在哪里呢
What's wrong? What's going on?
怎么啦 究竟是怎么回事
Watch out!
危险
Emouri!
江守
Takizawa-kun!
泷泽
Emouri, you are...
江守 你
Takizawa-kun, you are also...
泷泽 你也
We're out.
我们出局了
How come?
真不甘心啊
Thank you.
谢谢你们
Thanks to you, I'm still alive.
多亏你们救了我
This is the first time someone thanked me like this.
我第一次被人这样感谢
Feels not bad.
感觉真不错
The rest is up to you, Moroboshi.
诸星 剩下的就拜托你了
Don't worry.
交给我吧
Akira!
小晃
Shinya!
进也
Counting Ran-kun and Conan-kun,
这样剩下的
there are only four people left now.
包括小兰和柯南只有四人了
Well done, Jack the Ripper!
干得好 开膛手杰克
Turn this world into hell!
把这个世界变成地狱吧
Hurry up! Go through the back door!
快点 快从后门走
Run, Haibara!
快跑 灰原
That way!
往那边
Watch out!
小心
Haibara, are you alright?
灰原 你没事吧
Don't give up, Kudo-kun!
不能放弃哦 工藤
Although we can't find that character to help us,
虽然找不到帮助我们的角色
you are our Sherlock Holmes.
但对我们而言你就是福尔摩斯
You have this ability.
你 你拥有这种能力
There is no case that Sherlock Holmes can't solve, right?
没有什么案子是福尔摩斯解决不了的对吧
Ai-kun.
小哀
Hurry up!
快点快点
Get out of here!
快出去避难
Behind you!
后面
Stop right there!
给我站住
Bye, you'll be safe with the police.
再见 只要和警察在一起就安全了
Hey, kid!
啊 小弟弟
I haven't asked your name yet.
我还没问你的名字呢
My name is Conan Edogawa.
我叫江户川柯南
The same name as your creator's.
跟你们的创造者的名字一样
Conan?
柯南
I will not let you run away.
绝对不会让你逃掉
How's it going?
怎么样了
Conan-kun and the others have run into Jack the Ripper.
柯南他们遇到开膛手杰克了
They're chasing him now.
现在正在追他
Charlie Cross Station?
查理克罗斯车站
Conan-kun, you go up first.
柯南 你先上去
Things are going from bad to worse.
真是最糟糕的情况啊
What's the problem?
有什么问题吗
On the last train from Charlie Cross Station,
从查理克罗斯开出的最后一班列车
there will be the final and most dangerous climax of the story.
这是最危险的高潮结局
Jack the Ripper blended in with the passengers in disguise.
开膛手杰克 化装后混在乘客当中
Please gather all the passengers in one carriage.
请将乘客集中到同一节车厢中
I see.
知道了
Mr. Conductor, please listen to me.
列车长先生 请听我说
Everyone, please put your hands in the air
那么各位 请举起双手
to make sure you don't have the murder weapon in our hands.
好让我们确认手上是否持有凶器
Let me hear how you deduce it.
让我好好听听你的推理吧
I will now explain to you
那么我现在就来说明一下
the information written by Mr. Holmes.
福尔摩斯先生所写的资料内容
Honey Charleston, the second victim
混在这里的开膛手杰克
murdered by Jack the Ripper, who is hiding here,
所杀的第二个人 哈妮查理斯特
used to get married in a town called Windsor.
在一个名叫温沙的小镇结婚
But this woman was a dreamer.
不过她是个充满梦想的女性
Ten years ago, she left her husband and son for London.
十年前抛弃丈夫和儿子前往伦敦
These two rings
这两只戒指
were left behind at the scene where Honey Charleston was killed.
是哈妮查理斯特遇害现场的遗留物
One belongs to Honey,
一个是哈妮的
but the other, exactly same in design as the last one,
另外一个虽然拥有同样的设计
doesn't fit either of Honey's fingers.
却和哈妮任何一个手指的尺寸都不合
Here's what Mr. Holmes deduced.
对此 福尔摩斯先生是这样推理的
Could these two rings
这两只戒指会不会是
be proof of paternity between the victim, Honey Charleston and Jack the Ripper?
受害者哈妮查理斯特 与开膛手杰克之间亲子关系的证明
Are you saying that this smaller ring belongs to Jack the Ripper?
难道说这只小戒指是开膛手杰克的吗
Yes.
是的
Honey put the same shaped ring
哈妮是把同样形状的戒指
on her son's finger before she left home.
套在儿子的手指上然后离家出走的
Does that mean Jack the Ripper killed his own mother?
那么说 开膛手杰克杀害了自己的母亲
According to the information,
根据资料
Honey Charleston was murdered on September 8th.
哈妮查里斯特遭到杀害的9月8日
It happened to be the second Saturday of every month, the time when the church in the Whitechapel area
正好是每月第二个周六白教堂地区的教堂举办的
holds a parent-child bazaar to sale items made by parents and children.
将亲子共同制作的东西拿来拍卖的义卖活动之日
Jack the Ripper probably knew about it, too.
开膛手杰克大概也知道这件事吧
Even this kind of thing was written in?
连这个都有写啊
That is to say,
就是说
Jack the Ripper wanted to participate in the bazaar with his mother,
开膛手杰克因为很想跟母亲一起参加义卖会
that's why he left the ring?
所以才留下戒指的是吗
Mhm, I guess so.
嗯 好像是这意思
So the motive for the murder was resentment against his mother for abandoning him.
那么杀人的动机是对抛弃自己的母亲的怨恨
I've had enough! I didn't do anything bad.
真是的 我又没做什么坏事
Why does everyone hate me?
大家都在排挤我
But...
可是
Interwoven in the desire for killing is a fusion of love and hate.
那是爱与恨融为一体的杀意
How pathetic.
真是悲哀
I heard that he chose the unrelated woman as the first victim
选择毫无关系的女人作为第一个受害者
just to confuse the police.
听说只是为了迷惑警察的视线
But there was a third and fourth victim.
可是还有第三和第四个受害者
Professor Moriarty's brilliant education
莫里亚蒂教授的英才教育
turned Jack the Ripper into an abnormal criminal.
将开膛手杰克培养成了性格异常的罪犯
Even though he has avenged himself on his mother,
就算对母亲的仇恨已经报了
he still continued to attack women who resembled his mother.
不过他仍然继续袭击跟自己母亲很像的女人
Which one is he?
是 是哪一个
He had been wearing the same ring since he was a child.
如果从小就一直戴着同样尺寸的戒指的话
What do you think will that finger be like?
你想那根手指会变成什么样呢
I presume that among the ten fingers,
也许十根手指里面
only the finger that had worn the ring was unusually thin
只有那根手指特别的细
Jack the Ripper
开膛手杰克
is you.
就是你
But that person is a woman.
那个人是女人耶
The ring finger on the right hand is so thin.
右手的无名指好细
I'll handle him.
交给我
Don't go, Ran-nee-chan!
不可以 小兰姐
Oh no, it's a smoke bomb.
可恶 是烟雾弹
Open the window!
把窗户打开
They're gone.
不 不见了
Hey!
喂
All the passengers have disappeared.
乘客全部都消失了
What's going on?
这是怎么回事
All right, let's find out who killed Kashimura too.
那么 我们也来找出杀害坚村的凶手吧
You already know who the killer is?
你知道凶手是谁了吗
The point is how the killer prepared the murder weapon.
问题在于凶手是如何准备凶器的
There's a metal detector at the entrance of the city hall.
这个米花市政厅入口处设置了金属探测器
So the only explanation we can think of is that
因此可以想到的只能是
the murder weapon was arranged in the venue from the beginning.
凶器是从一开始就布置在会场里的东西
But where is it?
可是 那个东西在哪里
Among the bronze statues in the venue,
晚会会场里的铜像
there was one statue holding a short sword.
其中有一尊握着短剑
There were so many guests in the venue.
会场里面有那么多客人
If someone pulled it out, people would definitely see it.
要是去拔那个东西肯定会被人看到的
He pulled it off when the lights went out.
趁会场的灯光熄灭时拔下来的
He has determined the time of action in advance according to the schedule.
事先就根据时间表确定时机了
But, if the sword was missing,
可是 要是短剑不见了的话
someone would have noticed it, right?
应该会有人发现的吧
He put a fake one on it.
他放了假的在上面
He put a sword made of cardboard and aluminum foil or something.
用纸箱纸板和铝箔纸之类的东西做成的短剑
Are you saying that the sword in the statue's hand now is the murder weapon?
那现在铜像手上拿的就是作案时使用的短剑咯
Yes.
是的
I have asked someone to do the luminol test and detect fingerprints on the sword.
刚才我已请人做了短剑的鲁米诺反应及指纹的调查
We found the blood of the same blood type as Kashimura on the blade,
测出与坚村一样的血型
and fingerprints on the hilt.
剑柄上也找到了指纹
It's your fingerprint.
是你的指纹哦
Mr. Schindler.
辛多拉社长
Of course it is.
那是当然的
The bronze statues were moved from my house.
铜像是从我的家里搬来的
This is the surveillance video
这是在案发时间前后
taken at the party around the time of the crime.
晚会现场的监视器所拍的录像
Luckily, there were cameras all around the venue,
幸亏会场四周都装有监视器
so all the angles I need can be recorded.
所以我想要的角度都能录到
Moroboshi kicked the ball into the bronze statue, knocking down the sword.
诸星少年的球踢到了铜像上撞落了短剑
Then he picked up the sword,
然后他把剑捡起来
and put it back into the statue's hand
插回了铜像的手里
I see.
原来如此
If the sword kicked down was real,
如果刚才踢下来的短剑是真的
that boy's fingerprints would have been detected.
应该也会检测出少年的指纹才对
But only Mr. Schindler's fingerprints were detected on the sword.
可是短剑上只有辛多拉社长一个人的指纹
Humph. It's because I touched the sword after that boy.
哼 因为少年碰过后我也摸过那把剑
His fingerprints were covered up by mine.
所以他的指纹被我盖掉了
Mr. Kudo.
工藤先生
Found it.
找到了
We found the sword made of cardboard and aluminum foil
用纸箱纸板和铝箔纸做的短剑
in the garbage dump in the basement.
在地下室的垃圾收集场里被找到了
How about the fingerprints?
指纹呢
Just as Mr. Kudo said,
正如工藤先生所说的
there are the fingerprints of both Moroboshi and Mr. Schindler.
有诸星少年和辛多拉社长两人的指纹
If there is someone other than the boy who put fingerprints on the fake sword,
如果假的短剑上沾有少年之外的人的指纹
then that person must be the culprit.
那一定就是犯人的指纹
Nonsense!
胡说
I'll protest to the Japanese government.
我要向日本政府抗议
Besides, I had no motive to kill Kashimura.
何况我根本没有杀害坚村的动机
No one there.
没人
There's only the locomotive room ahead.
再过去只有机车室了
Driver is not there.
没有司机
We gotta stop the train first.
总之先把列车停下来
The brakes are broken.
刹车被破坏了
It's accelerating.
不断地在加速
Hey, we still can't find her,
喂 不找到那个姐姐的话
I'm afraid things are gonna go out of control.
恐怕就要糟糕啦
Ran!
兰
Where are you?
你在哪
Where did you go?
跑到哪里去了
Wait a minute.
等一下
There she is!
找到了
Ran-nee-chan!
小兰姐
Don't come over!
不要 不要过来
I roped myself and this lady together.
我用绳子把自己跟这位小姐绑在一起
That means if I fall, she will fall with me.
就是说如果我掉下去的话她也会跟我一起掉下去
Come on, what are you gonna do?
来吧 你想怎么出招
Damn it!
可恶
I heard that the sword on the bronze statue
听说铜像上的短剑是
is an antique family heirloom of the Schindler family, isn't it?
辛多拉家族历代家传的古董宝贝 是吧
Yes, you're right.
你说的没错
Why would you use this sword as the murder weapon?
这样的短剑你为什么要拿来做凶器呢
Why did you have to use this sword as the murder weapon,
为什么凶器一定要是这把短剑呢
in that case?
如果这样假设的话
What on earth do you want?
你究竟想要什么
Jack the Ripper.
开膛手杰克
What do I want?
想要什么
You've avenged yourself by killing your mother,
杀死母亲 报了多年的怨恨后
what more do you want?
现在你还想要什么
I want to live.
我想要活下去
I want the blood of sin flowing in my body
让流在我身体里的罪恶之血
to pass on to the next century by Noah's ark.
乘着诺亚方舟流传到下个世纪
That's why you killed Kashimura, right?
这就是你杀害坚村的动机吧
Jack the Ripper's blood,
开膛手杰克的血液
as if sitting on Noah's ark,
仿佛是坐上了诺亚方舟
now still exists in the world.
一直存活到现在
You're the descendant of Jack the Ripper, aren't you?
你是开膛手杰克的子孙 对吧
Descendant...
开 开膛手杰克的
of Jack the Ripper.
子孙
Hiroki probably found out about this through the DNA Search Project.
弘树可能是通过DNA探查程序得知了这件事
The giant of the IT industry
IT产业的巨头居然是
is the descendant of a serial killer a hundred years ago.
一百年前连续杀人恶魔的子孙
If this comes to light,
要是被世人知道的话
you will lose everything.
你就会失去一切
So, to silence Hiroki, you forced him to commit suicide.
所以为了灭口 你逼迫弘树自杀
Furthermore, you killed Kashimura.
还杀害了坚村
That was when Hiroki came to see my collections.
那是弘树来看我的收藏品时
It was said to be a gold cup used by the Egyptian Pharaoh Khufu.
据说这是埃及法老胡夫使用过的黄金杯
Next is the Buddhist Text of the monk Ganjin.
接下来是鉴真和尚的佛典
And this is the original manuscript of Rampo Edogawa's "psychological test".
这是江户川乱步的"心理测试"的亲笔原稿
Awesome!
好棒哦
What's this short sword?
这把短剑呢
That's...
那个是
It's said to be
据说是
the murder weapon used by the evil serial killer
一百年前的连续杀人恶魔
Jack the Ripper a hundred years ago.
开膛手杰克所使用过的凶器
Nobody knows if it's true.
是不是真的就不知道了
In order to do the experiment,
弘树为了做实验
Hiroki collected information from everyone around him and entered it into the computer.
于是收集了身边所有人的资料输入了电脑
The DNA of Honey Charleston detected from the short sword
从短剑中检测出来的哈妮查理斯特的DNA
is identical to your DNA.
和你的DNA一致
So you got scared.
于是你感到害怕
If Hiroki found out
因为万一弘树发现
Jack the Ripper is Honey's son,
开膛手杰克是哈妮的儿子
then it's only a matter of time before he knows that
那么知道你是开膛手杰克子孙的事
you are the descendant of Jack the Ripper.
也只是时间早晚的问题
I am scared of...
我很害怕
of this sinful blood flowing in my body.
流在我体内的这种可怕的血
What does it matter if it's the blood of an evil killer or not?
是杀人恶魔的血又如何
What does it matter what the world thinks of you?
世人的看法又如何
Why don't you fight against it?
为什么你不加以抗争呢
Just like Conan-kun and the others are doing now.
就像现在的柯南他们一样
Tomas Schindler
托马斯辛多拉
I'm arresting you for the murder of Tadaaki Kashimura.
我以涉嫌杀害坚村忠彬的罪名逮捕你
You can't catch me by dodging.
光会逃的话是抓不到我的
In ten minutes we'll arrive at the terminal.
还有十分钟就到终点站了
What will happen to this driverless train?
这辆无人驾驶的列车会怎样呢
But...
不过
Looks like you'll die even before the train enters the station.
看来在冲进车站之前你们就会升天
Conan-kun, behind you!
柯南 后面
Game over, kid!
到此为止了 小鬼
Conan-kun!
柯南
Let go of four eyes!
放开眼镜
Moroboshi-kun!
诸星
Are you okay?
你没事吧
I'm fine.
还好吧
All right, where should I start cutting?
好 要从哪里开始割你呢
What should I do?
该怎么才好呢
Shinichi.
新一
What would Shinichi do at this point?
新一在这时候会怎样做呢
I really like what Holmes said at that time.
我喜欢福尔摩斯当时所说过的一句话
Do you know what it is?
你知道是什么吗
No, I don't.
不知道
That is,
那就是
if I can really destroy you,
如果真的可以将你毁灭的话
I'm glad to embrace death for the sake of the public.
为了公众的利益我会很乐意迎接死亡
Four eyes!
眼镜
Reichenbach Falls, Conan-kun!
莱辛巴赫瀑布哟 柯南
Aren't you...
难道
Sorry I can't be with you until the end.
对不起 不能陪你到最后
Stop, Ran!
别这样 兰
No way!
不会吧
Damn it!
可恶
Conan-kun, I trust you.
柯南 我相信你
Ran!
兰
Four eyes, we must stop the train.
眼镜 我们得把列车停住
Hey, we can't survive if we don't stop the train, right?
喂 如果不把列车停下我们还能存活下去吗
We haven't won the game yet!
我们还不能说已经赢了这场游戏啊
Stand up, four eyes!
给我站起来 眼镜
There are still 48 lives counting on us.
我们身上还肩负着48条人命呢
Are you going to fail them?
难道你想辜负大家的希望吗
Idiot, I don't want to give up either!
傻瓜 我也不想放弃啊
Think about it.
你仔细想想
The train is accelerating.
列车正在不断加速
The train is moving at approximately 100 kilometers per hour.
列车的速度大约100公里
The train will arrive at the terminal in less than 5 minutes.
还有不到5分钟就到达终点站
The only way to save us
让大家得救的唯一方法
is to cut the connecting part between the locomotive and carriages.
只有切断火车头与客车车厢的连接部分才行
But how can we possibly break the connecting part
可是只靠我们两人的力量
with only two of us?
根本掰不动那个连接部分
Yes.
没错
I did think that we could make it with Ran's help.
本来想靠和小兰一起合力还能办得到
That's why Noah's Ark
所以"诺亚方舟"那家伙
made all the passengers disappeared.
才把所有的乘客都变没了
That's it.
不行了
There's nothing I can do.
已经没办法了
I failed, dad.
我已经不行了 爸爸
Hey, hey, hey! Don't give up!
喂喂 不要放弃啊
You must find a way to survive!
你总得想办法活下去
and save Ran's life!
救活兰的性命啊
Shinichi.
新一
You are not yet covered in blood.
你们还没有浑身浴血
You are still alive, aren't you?
你们还活着不是吗
Have you already given up?
你们已经放弃了吗
But you have already
你们明明已经
put your hands on the knot of the truth.
把手放在了解开真相的绳结上了
Wrapped in the colorless rope of life
在人生这条无色的绳索中
is a red thread called murder.
缠绕着一条叫作杀人的红色绳索
Isn't it our job to untie this knot?
而我们的工作不就是解开这个结吗
Holmes?
福尔摩斯
He should be in Dartmoor.
他应该去了达特莫尔才对啊
Is it a bug?
难道是程序错误
What does that mean?
这是什么意思
Jack the Ripper is already dead.
开膛手杰克明明已经死了
Why do we still have to be covered in blood?
为什么我们还得浑身浴血
That's it.
是这个
So this is what it means.
原来是这个意思
Cargo room!
货车车厢
Hey, wait!
喂 等一下
What are you going to do?
到底是怎么回事
Don't ask! Just follow me!
先别问 快过来
Break the wine barrels with that axe hanging there.
用挂在那里的斧头敲破装红酒的桶
Be quick!
快点
Dive down when I give you an order.
听到我叫就潜下去
Okay.
好
Right now!
现在
Where are their voices?
他们两人的声音呢
We can't hear anything yet.
现在还听不到任何声音
Conan! My dear lord!
柯南神明大人
Please save Ran.
求你救救兰
So that's it
原来如此
This is what he called covered in blood.
这就是浑身浴血啊
It means using the red wine to reduce the impact force.
原来是用红葡萄酒来减轻冲撞时的冲击力的意思
Thanks to you, we're saved, Holmes.
多亏你才得救了 福尔摩斯
No, father.
不 爸爸
Four eyes, you're awake.
眼镜你醒来啦
Looks like you won.
看样子是你赢了
You are...
你
I had guessed right.
果然是这样啊
I'm glad that I trusted you.
相信你实在是太好了
Thank you.
谢谢你
You're too polite.
不客气
Noah's Ark.
诺亚方舟
Maybe it's better to call you Hiroki-kun.
还是叫你弘树比较好吧
You used Moroboshi-kun's data
你借用了诸星的数据
and participated in this game with us, right?
一起参加了这个游戏是吧
When did you find out?
你是什么时候发现的
No need to worry.
你不用担心
I've cut off communication with the real world now.
现在我已经把跟现实世界的通信切断了
The first time I found it was strange was at Big Ben.
最初觉得奇怪是在大笨钟那里
You noticed it before the hour hand moved.
你在时针移动之前就觉察到了
You were trying to tell us
那是你想告诉我们
the meaning of the time on Big Ben, right?
大笨钟所显示时间的意思 对吧
Then it was the soccer.
接着是足球
At that time, you said it was a dirty ball, and then threw it in the back.
那时你说球脏就把它扔到了后面
Moroboshi is crazy about soccer.
对于一个少年球迷而言
It's impossible for him to not be interested in soccer from a hundred years ago.
不可能对一百年前的足球没有兴趣
Despite all the dangers you put us in,
虽然你让我们遭遇了种种危险
you believe that we would unite to overcome all the crises.
其实你相信我们一定会团结一致克服所有的危机
Don't you?
不是吗
The rebirth of Japan
所谓要让日本重生
doesn't mean wiping out the second and third generations of Japan,
并不是指抹杀第二三代的子孙
but making them overcome obstacles without parents' strength.
不依赖父母的力量跨越障碍
What you expect is that we can grow up through the game.
你期待的是我们能通过游戏来成长
You can't make yourself ruthless.
你无法使自己变得冷酷无情
The appearance of Holmes at the end is the evidence.
最后出现的福尔摩斯就是证据
In the final climax, you still let the character who can help us make an appearance.
在最后的高潮还是安排了帮助我们的角色出场
The reason I borrowed Moroboshi-kun's body to participate in the game
之所以要借诸星的身体潜入游戏
is because I want to play with my friends.
就是想跟朋友们一起玩
Even if it's just once.
哪怕一次也好
Because I'm always working.
因为我总是在工作
I'm sorry to put you all in danger.
对不起 让你们经历危险
But I really enjoyed myself in it.
可是 我真的玩得好开心
I really envy you.
而且 我好羡慕
Even through you and your father are apart, you two can still communicate from mind to mind.
即使分开 心灵仍能沟通的你和你父亲
Your father avenged my father.
你父亲帮我父亲报了仇
Thank you.
谢谢
It's almost time to say goodbye.
差不多该告别了
Your heart
弘树的心
will be beating in Noah's Ark forever, right?
永远都活在"诺亚方舟"里 对吧
If a computer like me continue to exist,
如果像我这种电脑继续存在下去的话
it will only be used by adults to do bad things.
只会被大人们用来做坏事
Artificial intelligence or something
人工智能什么的
can not yet exist in the world.
还不能够出现在这世界上
All right, go back to your world.
好了 你回你的世界去吧
When you wake up,
等你醒了之后
I hope you can tell everyone one thing.
希望你能告诉大家一件事
Life in reality is not as easy as in the game.
现实中的人生不像游戏中那样简单
I hope you can meet your father.
希望你能见到你父亲
Goodbye.
再见了
Shinichi Kudo.
工藤新一
Ran!
兰
Looks like he made it.
看来他成功了
Thank god! You're back safe!.
太好了 安然无恙地回来了
It was so fun!
好好玩哦
I tried very hard!
我很努力哦
Well done!
了不起
Conan-kun, thank you for bringing us back to life.
柯南 谢谢你让我们复活
We worked hard too, didn't we?
我们也很努力了 对吧
It was really a great adventure!
经历了非常棒的冒险啊
It's better in the real world.
还是现实世界比较好啊
What's going on?
到底发生了什么事啊
I knew that you'd make it.
我就相信柯南一定会成功的
But Ran-nee-chan,
但是小兰姐姐
wasn't it too reckless to pull that guy down?
拉着那家伙一块跳下去是不是太乱来了
Because I remembered a line from Sherlock Holmes that Shinichi likes.
因为我想起了新一喜欢的福尔摩斯的一句话
You mean the line that Holmes said
你是说福尔摩斯和莫里亚蒂教授
when he first met with Professor Moriarty?
第一次见面时说的那句话吗
Strange. How did you know that?
奇怪 你是怎么知道的
Oh, it's just...
哎呀 这个
I heard it from Shinichi-nii-chan too.
我也是从新一哥哥那里听来的
So that's how it is.
原来是这样啊
Anyway, thanks to his nagging,
还多亏他缠着我们讲
we were saved this time.
所以这次我们才得救了
Didn't I say
不是说了
there is no need to say the word "nagging"?
"缠"字是多余的吗
Ran!
兰
Dad!
爸爸
Great! Great!
太好了 太好了
You're back safe!
平安无事
It took too long for you this time.
对你来说 这次时间花太久了啊
Ah. That was fun.
啊 太好玩了
Noah's Ark is going to end his life.
"诺亚方舟"打算结束自己的生命
Rest in peace, Hiroki-kun.
安息吧 弘树
I must practice well to impress them!
为了不被他们小看 我要好好练习才行